Jean De Marco Papers
Jean De Marco Papers
1945-1964
De Marco, Jean, 1898-
0.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American sculptor, often of religious subjects. Born in Paris. Collection includes biographical material including a scrapbook of photographs of De Marco's work (1963-1964); correspondence (1954-1963); and published material about De Marco.
148937
Biographical History
Sculptor Jean De Marco (1898-1990) was born in Paris, France on May 2, 1898. He studied at the Ecole National des Arts Decoratifs in Paris and later taught sculpture at the Boston Museum of Fine Arts School and the National Academy of Design, of which he was a member. He was also a member of the National Sculpture Society and the National Institute of Arts and Letters.
De Marco's work often had religious themes or subjects. Examples of his religious work may be seen at Notre Dame University, the House of Theology in Centerville, Ohio, and the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception in Washington, D.C. His non-religious works include those at the U.S. Capitol in Washington, the Museum of Modern Art and the Brooklyn Museum, and the War Memorial at the Presidio in San Francisco.
De Marco's work has been shown at the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, the Art Institute of Chicago, the National Academy of Design, the 1939 World's Fair, and the Boston Museum of Fine Arts. He has won awards from the American Academy of Arts and Letters, the National Academy of Design, and the National Sculpture Society, as well as the Daniel Chester French Award and the Henry Hering Medal.
De Marco and his wife, sculptress Clara Fasano, divided their time between New York City and Greenwich, Connecticut.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Jean De Marco Papers are divided into four series. Biographical material contains a scrapbook with photographs of De Marco's work, biographical notes by him, and a catalogue with biographical information from the National Academy of Design School of Fine Arts. Correspondence both incoming and outgoing, separated. Subject files contains photographs of De Marco and his work and a scrapbook of the dedication of the War Memorial at the Presidio in San Francisco. Published material includes exhibition notices and magazine articles about De Marco.
Arrangement of the Collection
Incoming correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent; outgoing correspondence is arranged chronologically. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by subject. Published material is arranged alphabetically by type.
Related Material
See also the
Clara Fasano Papers
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Sculptors; De Marco, Jean, 1898-; Art, American.; Art, American -- 20th century.; French Americans.; Sculptors, United States.; Sculpture, American.; Sculpture, American, 20th century.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Artists.; Sculptors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Jean De Marco, 1964.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Miscellaneous, 1963-1964; undated; scrapbook with photographs of De Marco's work, biographical notes by him, and a catalogue with biographical information from the National Academy of Design School of Fine Arts. (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming, A-Z, 1954-1955; 1957-1961,; undated (Box 1)
  - Outgoing, 1964; undated (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Photographs of De Marco, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Photographs of De Marco's work, undated (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, West Coast memorial, 1960 (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Exhibition notices
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1950 (Box 1)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Magazine articles about
    - Bennett Alumnae Bulletin, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Bennett Alumnae Bulletin, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Mosaic, 1960 (Box 1)